<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title level="a" xml:lang="eng">Tidhar - Encyclopedia of the founders and builders of Israel </title>
           <respStmt>
               <resp>
                  <name>Snir Cohen</name>
                  <name>Snir Burkush</name>
               </resp>
               <orgName>BGU</orgName>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>DH CS Course in BGU year of 2019 semester alef</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
<bibl>Volume: #11 ,Page: 3753 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/11/3753</bibl><bibl>Volume: #11 ,Page: 3755 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/11/3755</bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="heb">
      <body>
     <head> <persName>ג'ראלד ברונפמן</persName>

</head>
         <div><p> מהפעילים לטובת מדינת ישראל. Mr Gerald )Jocob( Bornfman was born at Yorkton, Saskatchewan, )Canada( De.1911 ,22 cember 

 Son of Harry Bronfman )see his biography in this book(.

 Mother: Ann )Hinde( daughter of Mr Gallaman.

 On February 9, 1941, married Marjorie Meta, daughter of Jacob Sshechter of New York.

 Has four children: Joan Eileen, Corinne Marcia, Judith Lynn, Jeffrey Mark. Educated : Western Public Schools,

 Montreal High School, McGill University )B. Comm.(

 Began with Distillers Corporation-Seagrams Ltd., Montreal, Que., and SeagramDistillers Corporation, New York. President, Kensington Industries Inc. Chairman of Executive Committee and

 Director, Dominion Dairies Ltd., Montreal, Que.


 Director; Pinatel Piece Dye Works Ltd., Joliette, Que.; Stressteel Corporation, Wilkes-Barre, Pa. Vice-Chairman, Combined Jewish Appeal, Montreal, for number of years. Member, Board of Trustees, Federation of Jewish Community Services, Montreal.

 Member: Executive Committee Canadian Red Cross Society, Quebec Division; National Council Canadian Institute for the Blind ; National Council of American Joint Distribution Committee ; Life Governor, Verdun Prote3tant Hospital ; active in other communal and philanthropic causes. Member, Executive Committee, Montreal Symphony Orchestra; Centennial Advisory Committee, Montreal Museum of Arts. Served with R. C. A. F. in Word War .II Rank: Squadron Leader. Decoration: U. S. Legion of Merit, Degree of Officer. Clubs : Montefiore )Montreal( ; Elm. Ridge Country )Dorval, Que.( Societies and Fraternities : Phi Lamba. Phi. Mu Sigma, B'nei Brith, McGill Graduates. Recreations : Golf, Photography, Skiing.

</p></div>
         <div type="bibliogrphy">
            <listBibl>
<bibl>Volume: #11 ,Page: 3753 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/11/3753</bibl><bibl>Volume: #11 ,Page: 3755 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/11/3755</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
