<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title level="a" xml:lang="eng">Tidhar - Encyclopedia of the founders and builders of Israel </title>
           <respStmt>
               <resp>
                  <name>Snir Cohen</name>
                  <name>Snir Burkush</name>
               </resp>
               <orgName>BGU</orgName>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>DH CS Course in BGU year of 2019 semester alef</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
<bibl>Volume: #11 ,Page: 3867 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/11/3867</bibl>         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="heb">
      <body>
     <head> <persName>יעקב בלאושטיין</persName>

</head>
         <div><p> Blaustein, Jakob, U.S., business executive; b. Baltimore, Md., Sept. 30, 1892; s. Louis and Henrietta )Gittelsohn( ; m. Hilda Van Leer Katz, June 20, 1925. Dir., member, exec. comm.; 1910Amer. Oil Co., co-founder with father, )merged with Pan. Amer. Petroleum and

 Transport Co., 1933(, pres., 1933-37; Mexican Petroleum Corp., Me., pres., 1933-37; Pan Amer. Petroleum and Transport Co.; Pan Amer. Refining Corp. ; Pan Amer. Pipe Line Co.; Pan Amer. Production Co.; Mexican Petroleum Corp., Ga.; Pan Amer. Gas Co.; Lord Baltimore Filling Stations, Inc.; pres. and dir., Amer. Trading and Production Corp.; dir., advisory comm. : Union Trust Co., Md.; U.S. Fidelity and Guaranty Co.; former pres., Overseas News Agency. Consultant, Amer. delegation, UN Conf., S.F., 1945; chmn, Amer. ;1946delegation, Conf. of Jewish Orgs., London, chmn, AJ Comm. Deleg., Paris Peace Conf., 1949; 2 missions to Israel at request of Prime Minister; co-chmn, Consultative Council of Jewish Orgs. to Economic and Social Council, UN; dir.: Asso. Jewish Charities, Baltimore )former pres.(; JDC; United Service for New Americans; Amer. Financial and Development Corp. for Israel; Amer. Fund for Israel Oorgs.; Amer. Assn for UN; Natl Conf. of Christians and Jews; Weizmann Inst. of Science; CJFWF; Baltimore Symphony Orchestra; member: bd of govs, Hebrew U. of Jerusalem; bd of trustees, Harry S. Truman Library; pres., AJComm; Louis and Henrietta Blaustein Found., Inc.; member, Pres. Truman's Natl Advisory Bd on Mobilization Policy; acting chmn, marketing comm., member, supplies and distribution comm. and joint use facilities comm., U.S.

 Petroleum Administration for War, World War II; member, natl petroleum council, oil and gas div., U.S. Dept. of Interior; vicechmn, Natl Citizens Comm. for UN Day; vice-pres., Jewish Restitution Successor Org.; member, presidium, Conf. on Jewish Material Claims against Germany. Clubs: Phoenix and Suburban, Baltimore. (מתוך הספר 1955/56World Jewish Register ) 

</p></div>
         <div type="bibliogrphy">
            <listBibl>
<bibl>Volume: #11 ,Page: 3867 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/11/3867</bibl>            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
