<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title level="a" xml:lang="eng">Tidhar - Encyclopedia of the founders and builders of Israel </title>
           <respStmt>
               <resp>
                  <name>Snir Cohen</name>
                  <name>Snir Burkush</name>
               </resp>
               <orgName>BGU</orgName>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>DH CS Course in BGU year of 2019 semester alef</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
<bibl>Volume: #11 ,Page: 3804 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/11/3804</bibl><bibl>Volume: #11 ,Page: 3805 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/11/3805</bibl>
<bibl>Volume: #11 ,Page: 3806 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/11/3806</bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="heb">
      <body>
     <head> <persName>פיליפ מוריס קלוצניק</persName>

</head>
         <div><p> PHILLIP MORRIS KLUTZNICK

 נולד בקנסאס סיטי מו. (בארצות הברית), כ"ז תמוז תרס"ז (9.7.1907).

 לאביו<persName> מוריס קלוצניק</persName> ולאמו <persName>מיני</persName> לבית <persName>שפינדלר.</persName>

 השתלם באוניברסיטה בקנסאס (1924-25). האוניברסיטה של נבראסקה (בארצות הברית) (1925-26). קבל תואר L1.B.בקרייטון אוניברסיטה (אומהה) (1930). תואר כבוד D.H.L.מדרופסי קולדז' בקולוראדו (1954). ותואר Fellowבברנדיס אוניברסיטה.

 גמר משפטים וקיבל תואר עורך דין.

 ב-8 ביוני 1930 נשא לאשה את <persName>אטל</persName> לבית<persName> ריקס.</persName> Member, law firm, Beber, Klutznick, Beber and Kaplan, Omaha, and Klutznick, Beber &amp; Miller, Chicago, I11., since 1946; entered law practice, Omaha, 1930; appointed asst. corp. counsel, Omaha, 1933; special asst. to U.S. attorney gen. in slum clearance and housing matters, 1935-36; gen. counsel, Omaha Housing Authority, 1938-41; consultant to: U.S. Housing Administrator, 1940-41; Federal Housing Expeditor and Natl Housing Administr., since ;19461946; Public Housing Commn., since Defense Mobilizer Charles E. Wilson on housing and community facilities, 1951; regional ;1941-42co-ordinator, Div. of Defense Housing, ;1943-44asst. administr., Natl Housing Agency, appointed commissioner, Federal Housing Au;1944-46thority )FHA( by Pres. Roosevelt, member, vice-chmn, I11. State Housing Bd; instrumental in post-war development of Chicago suburb, Park Forest. Member: advisory bd., Inst. for Urban Land Use and Housing Studies, Columbia U., since 1947; bd. of govs.: Natl Assn of Housing Officials, 1944-46; Metropolitan Housing and Planning Council of Chi;1945-47cago; bd of dirs, Natl Housing Conf., .1946pres., Amer. Community Builders, since Interntl pres., B'nai BVith, since 1954, charter member, Kansas City chap. Aleph Zadek Aleph, 1923, grand Aleph Gadol )interntl pres., AZA(, 1925-26, editor, The Shofar, 1925-26, 1933, part-time exec. secy, Jr B'nai

 B'rith, 1926-33; pres.: Omaha B'nai B'rith ,1940-41lodge, 1930-31, dist. grand lodge, ,1941-44Supreme Lodge advisory council, Supreme Lodge, since 1953, member: lodge exec. commn., 1947-50; exec. commn., ADL Commn, since 1950, and chmn, Chicago exec. -1951comm., ADL, 1951-53, vice-chmn, ADL, 53; member: exec. comm., Joint Defense Appeal; Hillel Foundations Commn ; youth org. commn; vocational service commn; consultant to youth commn, since 1944; member: and

 ;1947counsel, Henry Monsky Found., since bd of trustees, Natl Jewish Hosp., Denver; Leo N. Levi Memorial Hosp., Hot Springs, Ark. Pres.: Omaha Zionist Dist., 1929; Omaha Bd of Jewish Edn, 1939-40; W. central states region, CJFWF, 1933; Omaha Jewish Philanthropies, 1934; budget commn., Omaha Fed. for Jewish Service, 1937-40; Amer. Housing Comm. for Israel, at request of Prime Minister, ,1946-491949-50; Jewish centers div., JWB, vice-pres., JWB, since 1949; vice-pres.: S.W. region, ZOA, 1931; World Fed. of YMHAs ;1947and Jewish Community Centers, since vice-chmn, Amer. Jewish Tercentenary; member: bd of dirs: Rassco Israel Corp.; Pal. Economic Corp., 1948-50; JNF; Conf. of Jewish Material Claims Against Germany; bd of gove, State of Israel Bonds; natl Council, Boy Scouts of Amer., Natl Jewish Comm. on Scouting; Lambda Alpha Legion of Honor, Aleph Zadek Aleph. Recipient: certificate of merit, Pres. Truman, 1947; Sam Beber outstanding alumnus award, 1951; award for Park Forest, Amer. Inst. of Architects; natl award of merit for Park Forest in neighborhood development contest, Natl Assn of Home Builders, 1951; award for service to humanity, District Grand Lodge


 of B'nai B'rith, 1952. Clubs: Standard; Ravisloe

 Country - both of Chicago; Cosmos, Wash.; Highland Country, Omaha. Ex Chairman of B'nai B'rith International .(1953-1959)Council,

 Honourary President of North American B'nai B'rith.

 Personal Consultant to President Dwight Eisenhower, United Nations Delegate, and lawyer.

 M. Klutznick is a dynamic speaker and personality. His recent election as National President of The American Friends of the

 Hebrew University crowns his work in scores of movements in many countries. An international town planner, he has been commissioned by to Israel Government to build a seaport city for a population of 150,000 near biblical "Ashdod".

 He is a Governor of the Hebrew University and was described in the book "Organization Man" as the epitome of communal leadership.

 אחרי שמר<persName> קנדי</persName> נבחר (1961) לנשיא ארצות הברית, בחר בו לחבר המשלחת האמריקאית באו"ם.

 הוא בעל לב יהודי חם. לא נתן דריסת רגל בבניברית למגמות התבוללות ועוזר למדינת ישראל בכל הזדמנות

 צאצאיו: <persName>בטילו, רישרד</persName> ז''ל, <persName>טומאס, ג'ימס, רוברט,</persName> <persName>סמואל.</persName>

</p></div>
         <div type="bibliogrphy">
            <listBibl>
<bibl>Volume: #11 ,Page: 3804 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/11/3804</bibl><bibl>Volume: #11 ,Page: 3805 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/11/3805</bibl>
<bibl>Volume: #11 ,Page: 3806 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/11/3806</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
