<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title level="a" xml:lang="eng">Tidhar - Encyclopedia of the founders and builders of Israel </title>
           <respStmt>
               <resp>
                  <name>Snir Cohen</name>
                  <name>Snir Burkush</name>
               </resp>
               <orgName>BGU</orgName>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>DH CS Course in BGU year of 2019 semester alef</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
<bibl>Volume: #14 ,Page: 4443 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/14/4443</bibl>         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="heb">
      <body>
     <head> <persName>פרופ' אברהם יצחק כץ (קאטש)</persName>

</head>
         <div><p> נולד בסלוב (פולין) א' אלול תרס"ח (10.8.1908).

 לאביו הרב <persName>ראובן כץ</persName> (רבה הראשי של עירית פ"ת. (ראך כרך ג', עמוד 1490). נפטר ט"ז חשון תשכ"ד - 3.11.1963) ולאמו<persName> רייכל</persName> בת הרב <persName>אברהם</persName> <persName>יצחק משכיל - לאיתן</persName> (אז רבה של חסלביץ ; ממשפחה המתיחסת, לפי ספר יוחסין שהיה מקובל בידה, על זרע<persName> דוד המלך</persName> ; היה במשפחה הדור ה-27 של רבנים בני רבנים ; משיצא צו המלכות ברוסיה לרישום שמות-משפחה קיבל את השם <persName>משכיל לאיתן,</persName> על שם החיבור על הש"ס מאת אחד מאבותיו, הגאון ר' אברהם בעל "יד אברהם" על "יורה דעה", "באר "אברהם" על הרמב"ם ו"מצפה איתן" על כל הש"ס).

 קבל חינוך מסורתי וכללי, בגמנסיה עברית בוילנה, בישיבת גרודנה (תחת הנהלתו של רבי <persName>שמעון שקופ</persName> זצ"ל. ניו-יורק אוניברסיטי, פרינסטון אוניברסיטי ודרופסי קולג'.

 משנת 1925 בארצות הברית.

 ב-20 לפברואר 1943 נשא לאשה את<persName> אסתר</persName> (אסתלה) בת<persName> אליעזר וואכטל.</persName>

 At the head of New York University's programs for the preservation and advancement of Jewish culture is Dr. Abraham I. Katsh.

 He is director of the Institute of Hebrew Studier in the Graduate School of Arts and Science, chairman of the department of Hebrew culture and education in the School of Education, curator of theUniversity's Library of Judaica and Hebraica, and charman of the faculty council of NYU's Jewish Culture Foundation.

 He also did graduata work at the Islamic Insfifute of Princeton University and in 1944 received a doctor of philosophy degree from the Dropsie

 College for Hebrew and Cognate Learning, Philadelphia. He now is a member of Dropsie's board of governors.

 He joined the NYU faculty in 1933 as an instructor. A year later, he introduced the first course in modern Hebrew to be taught at an American university. He became assistant professor of education and the first occupant of the chair of Hebrew culture and education in 1944. He was promoted .1947to associate professor in 1945 and professor in 1937Founded the Jewish Culture Foundation in and in 1942 established the Library of Judaica and

 Hebraica, which now has a collection of soma 25,000 rare volumes, estimated to be worth </p></div>
         <div type="bibliogrphy">
            <listBibl>
<bibl>Volume: #14 ,Page: 4443 ,URL: http://www.tidhar.tourolib.org/tidhar/view/14/4443</bibl>            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
